# Jordan Ellis Bechek

# Software Developer

I am, always have been, and always will be a problem solver and tinkerer, inquisitive in nature and imaginative at heart. I have been programming for seven years and am skilled in web development, database design, and mobile platform development.





bechek.jordan@gmail.com



Pittsburgh, PA



jbechek.github.io



in linkedin.com/in/jordan

# **Work Experience**

### **Computer Systems Analyst**

Northrop Grumman

09/2018 - Present

Canonsburg, PA

- Develop various data-driven web applications, using ColdFusion to integrate backend databases
- Assist with the finalization of the migration from Gentran to B2B

#### **EDI Intern**

Northrop Grumman

06/2018 - 09/2018

Canonsburg, PA

- Led the migration of business partners from FTP to SFTP using SSH2 key authentication, heightening security for EDI
- Developed data maps for inbound and outbound EDI using B2B Sterling Integrator

# **Application Support Intern**

Aires 🗹

05/2017 - 08/2017

Robinson, PA

- Developed dynamic, client-facing forms using XML and AJAX
- Maintained various database schemas for customer data using PL/SQL
- Worked closely with not only the Application Support team, but also with QA, Development, and Busniess teams to ensure client satisfaction

# **Education**

# **BA** in Computing and Information Studies Washington & Jefferson College

09/2014 - 05/2018

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- Minors in Neuroscience and Philosophy

## **Projects**

### Real-Time Bus Tracking System 🗹

Completed for Project Management Course

Tracks Freedom Transit's busses in real-time using an Android tracker app, and displays bus and route info through a client-facing web application; uses Google Firebase and Google Maps API

### Student's Edge Mobile Application 🗹

Based on project for App Design and Development Course

Hybrid app published on both the Google Play and Apple App Stores. Tracks students' classes, assignments, and grades; determines minimum required grades to reach student-set goal

### Data Storage System 🗹

Completed for Advanced Database Concepts Course

Transactional database and data warehouse system for a DJ service; MySQL was used to design, develop, and maintain the system, along with automated data transference from short- to long-term storage

# Languages & Software Skill Set

lava

HTML

CSS

**JavaScript** 

JSON

JQuery / JQuery Mobile

AngularJS

**XML** 

ColdFusion

**SQL** 

PL/SQL

MySQL

Cordova

Xcode

Android Studio

Amazon Alexa

**Eclipse** 

**NetBeans** 

Photoshop

Axure

IIRA

GitHub / Git

## **References**

### Charles Pfeffer, BS

EDI Manager Northrop Grumman 333 Technology Dr #250 Canonsburg, PA 15317, US Email: cpfeffer@opentrac.com

#### Charles T. Hannon, Ph.D.

Professor and Department Chair of CIS Washington & Jefferson College 50 S Lincoln St Washington, PA 15301, US Email: channon@washjeff.edu

#### Zach Hall, MIS

Manager of Application Support/Implementation Aires 6 Penn Center W #200 Pittsburgh, PA 15276, US Email: zhall@aires.com

#### Thomas Lombardi, DPS

Assistant Professor of Computer Information Systems University of the Virgin Islands Charlotte Amalie West St Thomas 00802, USVI Email: thomas.lombardi@uvi.edu

# **Awards & Accomplishments**

David and Kristin Steinburg Scholarship in Computing and Information Studies 2016 Recipient

Phi Beta Kappa Honor Society 2018 Inductee

Phi Sigma Tau Honor Society 2018 Inductee